Guide to the Lois Meek Stolz Psychology Case Interviews
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lois Meek Stolz psychology case interviews
1957-1958
SC0277
Stolz, Lois Meek, 1891-1984.
7.5 Linear feet
These papers contain transcripts and summary files of 41 interviews of parents, done in 1957 and 1958.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography
Born in Washington, D.C. in 1891, Lois Meek Stolz attended public schools, graduating from Washington Normal Schools in 1912. She taught school in the primary grades and attended George Washington University, graduating with an A.B. cum laude in 1921. Following that she earned her Ph.D. in 1925 at Columbia University, studying psychology under John Dewey among others. In 1924 she was recruited by the American Association of University Women to serve as Education Secretary and develop a national program of adult education. In 1929, she returned to Columbia as Professor of Education at Teachers College and also as Associate Director of the Child Development Institute, quickly becoming the Director. During this period Columbia Teachers College was the pre-eminent center in the field of education. Many of her doctoral students rose to positions of leadership in the field of child development. In 1938 she married Dr. Herbert Rowell Stolz and moved to Oakland, California. Herbert Stolz graduated from Stanford Medical School in 1914. He held administrative positions for the state of California and at the University of California, Berkeley where he was the first director of the Institute of Child Welfare. Lois joined the Institute in the late 1930s. They co-authored Somatic Development of Adolescent Boys, a classic in its field. During World War II, Lois worked for Kaiser Shipyards in Portland as Director of Child Service Centers. In 1947, she came to Stanford as a professor of psychology and started the doctoral program in child development in the School of Education. She authored Father Relations of War-Born Children in 1954. She received many awards and was honored many times by her peers and students. After becoming emeritus in 1957, Dr. Stolz worked on the Communication and Child Care Project at Stanford, culminating in the book, Influences on Parent Behavior, published in 1967. She died in Palo Alto on October 24, 1984 at the age of 93.
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain transcripts and summary files of 41 interviews of parents, done in 1957 and 1958. The families interviewed were in the Palo Alto area and were selected for their diversity of economic and cultural backgrounds. Each family had two parents and one or more children under the age of 9. Lois Stolz used the contents of these interviews as the source material for the book, Influences on Parent Behavior. The interviewers were faculty or graduate students from the Psychology Department at Stanford. There was an initial interview with the mother and father in their home or apartment, usually without the children. After that interviews were scheduled with the mother and father separately, typically 4 interviews of an hour each. Overall it varied from a low of 1 interview to a high of 6 interviews. The interviewer started out in the first interview with the parent asking about their children. They would direct the parent to describe each child. From there they tried to determine the roles the mother and father played in the raising of the children. The interviewer didn't discourage the parent from deviating from the question as long as the parent was revealing their attitudes toward child rearing. Often the interview would bring out problems with the children and marriage. The interviews could become quite emotional. The purpose of the interview was to gather the parent's attitudes and beliefs to child rearing. The taped interviews were transcribed and typed. No names were used to preserve the anonymity of the interviewees and each interview was given a case number. Upon conclusion of the interviews the interviewer wrote up a summary of their impressions of both the father and mother. After the initial interview, the interviewer prepared an "Initial Contact" form. This form contained information about the parents, how many children, background of parents, and observations on the parent's attitude and home.
Access Terms
Child rearing.; Family--United States; Parent and child
Collection Contents
- Case 1, Initial Contact, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Case 1, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Case 1, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Case 1, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Case 1, Father Interviews, Interview 6, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Case 1, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Case 1, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Case 2, Initial Contact, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Case 2, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Case 2, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Case 2, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 5, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Case 2, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Case 2, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Case 3, Initial Contact 1957; Case 2, Father Interviews, Interview 6, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Case 3, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Case 3, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 4, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Case 3, Father Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 7, 8, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Case 3, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 4, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Case 3, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Case 4, Initial Contact, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Case 4, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Case 4, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Case 4, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Case 4, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Case 4, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Case 5, Initial Contact, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Case 5, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Case 5, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Case 5, Father Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Case 5, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Case 5, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 6, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Case 6, Initial Contact, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Case 6, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Case 6, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Case 6, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Case 6, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Case 6, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Case 6, Mother Interviews, Interview 6, 7, 8, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Case 7, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Case 7, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Case 7, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Case 7, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 4, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Case 7, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Case 7, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Case 8, Initial Contact, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Case 8, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Case 8, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Case 8, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Case 8, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Case 9, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Case 9, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Case 9, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Case 9, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Case 9, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Case 9, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Case 10, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Case 10, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Case 10, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Case 10, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Case 10, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Case 11, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Case 11, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Case 11, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Case 11, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Case 11, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Case 12, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Case 12, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Case 12, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Case 12, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Case 12, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Case 12, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Case 13, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Case 13, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Case 14, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Case 14, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Case 14, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Case 14, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Case 14, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Case 15, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Case 15, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Case 15, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Case 15, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Case 15, Mother Interviews, Interview 2, 3, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Case 16, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Case 16, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Case 16, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Case 16, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 6, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Case 16, Father Interviews, Interview 7, 8, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Case 16, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Case 16, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Case 16, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Case 17, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Case 17, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Case 17, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Case 17, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Case 17, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Case 17, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Case 18, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Case 18, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Case 18, Pediatrician Interview, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Case 18, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Case 18, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Case 18, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Case 18, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 5, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Case 19, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Case 19, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Case 19, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Case 19, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Case 19, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Case 19, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Case 19, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Case 19, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Case 20, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Case 20, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Case 20, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Case 20, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Case 20, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Case 20, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Case 21, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Case 21, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Case 21, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Case 21, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Case 21, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Case 22, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Case 22, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Case 22, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Case 22, Father Interviews, Interview 2, 3, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Case 22, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Case 22, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Case 21, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Case 23, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Case 23, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Case 23, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Case 23, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Case 23, Father Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Case 23, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Case 23, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Case 23, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Case 24, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Case 24, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Case 24, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Case 24, Father Interviews, Interview 2, 3, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Case 24, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Case 24, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Case 24, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Case 25, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Case 25, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Case 25, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Case 25, Father Interviews, Interview 2, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Case 25, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Case 25, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Case 25, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Case 25, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Case 25, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 7, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Case 26, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Case 26, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Case 26, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Case 26, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Case 26, English Interview, Mother, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Case 26, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Case 26, Mother Interviews, Interview 2, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Case 26, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Case 26, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Case 27, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Case 27, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Case 27, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Case 27, Father Interviews, Interview 2, 3, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Case 27, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Case 27, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Case 27, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Case 28, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Case 28, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Case 28, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Case 28, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Case 28, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Case 29, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Case 29, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Case 29, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Case 29, Father Interviews, Interview 2, 3, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Case 29, Father Interviews, Interview 4, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Case 29, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Case 29, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 5, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Case 30, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Case 30, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Case 30, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Case 30, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Case 30, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Case 30, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Case 31, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Case 31, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Case 31, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Case 31, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Case 31, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Case 31, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Case 31, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Case 32, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Case 32, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Case 32, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Case 32, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Case 32, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Case 32, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 6, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Case 32, Mother Interviews, Interview 7, 8, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Case 33, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Case 33, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Case 33, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Case 33, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Case 33, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Case 33, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Case 33, Mother Interviews, Interview 5, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Case 34, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Case 34, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Case 34, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Case 34, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Case 34, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Case 34, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Case 34, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 5, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Case 35, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Case 35, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Case 35, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Case 36, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Case 36, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Case 36, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Case 36, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 3, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Case 37, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Case 37, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Case 37, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Case 37, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Case 37, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Case 37, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Case 37, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Case 38, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Case 38, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Case 38, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Case 38, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 4, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Case 38, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Case 38, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Case 38, Mother Interviews, Interview 4, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Case 39, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Case 39, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Case 39, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Case 39, Father Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Case 39, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 2, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Case 39, Mother Interviews, Interview 3, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Case 40, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Case 40, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Case 40, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Case 40, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Case 41, Initial Contact, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Case 41, Summary of Interviewer's Impressions of Case, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Case 41, Father Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Case 41, Mother Interviews, Interview 1, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 14)